

Abhay Saini D-Block, SF 17, Satellite Junction, Indus Satellite Green. IBD Township, Kalod Hala Pincode-452010 Indore(M.P)

abhaysaini.kanpur@yahoo.com

+91.9506090912



www.linkedin.com/in/abhay-saini-1aa8a190



Career Objective

A dedicated Supply Chain Analyst with extensive experience of 8 years in pharmaceuticals warehouse and making timely transportation arrangements. Strong emphasis on factors like Freight Optimization and Cost Avoidance. Proven track record in maintaining ideal inventory levels and managing capital and expense budget at different distribution warehouses.

Education

Masters, Business Administration

Sam Hingginbottom University of Agriculture. Technology and Sciences (SHUATS) Allahabad, Uttar Pradesh.

Post Graduated, Aug. 2018 Marks 55% Grade A

Bachelor, B.sc

Janta Shiksha Sansthan Mahavidyalaya Affiliated to Chhatrapati Shahu Ji Maharaj University, Kanpur. Division 2

Graduated, July 2015 Marks 49.05%

10+2MKG Inter College, Uttar Pradesh Board Allahabad.

Intermediate, June 2012 Marks 67.4% Division 1

Career Highlights

- Neiss Labs Ltd.
- Designation:- Branch Manager
- Duration:- From Jan. 2016 to till date
- Rohit surface Pvt Ltd. (Namaste India)
- Designation: Depot Manager
- Duration:- From Dec. 2014 to 31 Dec. 2015
- Arpan Fragrances (Archita Masale) Pvt Ltd.
- Designation:- Executive
- Duration:- From Jan 2014 to Dec. 2014
- Cadila Healthcare Pvt Ltd.
- Designation:- Executive
- Duration:-From Oct. 2012 to Dec. 2013

Skills

- Excel M.S. Office Tally

Work Experience

June-2013 - Dec.2014

Executive

Arpan Fragrances (Archita Masale) Pvt Ltd. Kanpur, Uttar Pradesh.

- Monitoring the sales & Collection of the region.
- Data updating on time in Tally and excel sheet.
- Dally monitoring of the activity of the Sales team.

Dec. 2014 to 31 Dec.2015

Depot Manager

Rohit surface Pvt Ltd (Namaste India)

Ghaziabad, Delhi-NCR

- Billing Submission.
- Managing the planning the route vehicles.
- Daily monitoring of the activity of the operation team for flow less operation.
- Acquiring the customer monitoring and retaining the existing customer provides solution of the customer query timely consignments delivery of the customer.
- Data updating on time in Microsoft Dynamics Nav"Ax"and excel sheet.

Jan 2016 to till date. **Branch Manager**Neiss Labs Ltd.

Indore, Madhya Pradesh

- Handling customer gueries and resolve issues...
- Ensure all report send to Head office on time.
- Daily monitoring all consignment should be dispatch on time.
- Achieved and maintained a 99.95 % level of service ensuring customer satisfaction.
- Managed an 10% reduction in labor cost by identifying the root cause.
- Improved attendance, housekeeping and general disciplines of the entire warehouse.
- Negotiated freight carrier contracts to reduce shipping cost
- Managed logistics of multiple shipments and deliveries within extreme time constraints.
- Reconciled inventory, monthly.
- Managed, supervised and trained 3 supervisors and 6 warehouse workers. Scheduled all staff shifts.
- Lowered carrier costs by reviewing existing contracts and bringing in new carriers.
- Managing branch work.

Computer Proficiency

- Diploma in Computer Application.
- Diploma in a Computer Accounting.

% Languages

- Hindi
- English

Personal Interests

Playing Chess

- Travelling
- Working on Computer

9 Personal Details

Father's Name: Mr. Mahesh Saini Marital Status: Single Birthday: August 17, 1995 Nationality: Indian

Gender: Male

Permanent Address:-Village & Post – Patara, Dist.-Kanpur Nagar, Pincode-209308

Declaration

I, Abhay Saini, hereby declare that the information contained herein is true and correct to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Abhay Saini Indore, Madhya Pradesh Nov 20, 2022



